<!-- encoding: utf-8 -->
<!-- Must be parsable as XML, otherwise including will fail, check with docserve -->
<html>
<head></head>
<body>
<!-- column to show on landingpage -->
<div class="col" id="featuredtopic">

<h3>Featured Topic: The new Checkmk Cloud</h3>
<p>
The latest offering from Checkmk is called Checkmk Cloud.
Checkmk Cloud is the SaaS platform designed for hybrid IT infrastructure monitoring, empowering an effortless setup and maintenance-free operation.
</p>

<h3>Highlights</h3>
<p>
Focus on your IT monitoring, not on operating Checkmk. 
Experience an always up-to-date Checkmk, with the latest features, security patches and much more.
</p>
<p class="buttonright">
<a href="#" id="morebutton">Find out more …</a>
</p>

<div id="ytbox">
<img src="../images/featured_saas.png" />
<!--  <img class="ytpreview" src="../images/featured_saas.jpg" /> -->
<div class="ytbanderole">
On YouTube:<br />
<b>Checkmk live-stream - Get insights into the new Checkmk Cloud</b>
</div>

</div><!--  end id featuredtopic -->
<div>
<!-- the overlay -->
<div id="topicopaque">
<div id="topicshadow">
<div class="innercols">
<!-- left column -->
<div class="col">
<h2>Checkmk Cloud – the highlights</h2>
<img src="../images/CEE.svg" align="left" width="80" style="margin: 10px;" />
<p>
Checkmk Cloud is the latest offering from Checkmk.
Experience the benefits of a hosted monitoring solution without having to worry about its administration:
</p>
<p>
<b>Hybrid and cloud monitoring</b> - Take advantage of centralized monitoring of cloud and on-premises resources, optimized for small to medium-sized hybrid infrastructures.
</p>
<p>
<b>Quick and easy onboarding</b> - Setup your monitoring in minutes with pre-configured settings and gain insight into your infrastructure and applications in no time.
</p>
<p>
<b>Low-maintenance operation</b> - Experience an always up-to-date monitoring solution with the latest features and security patches.
</p>
<p>
<b>High availability</b> - Benefit from a reliable, out-of-the-box monitoring solution hosted on AWS in Europe and North America. All site-specific data remains in the region.
</p>
<p>
<b>Optimal performance</b> - Scale with minimal latency thanks to regional hosting.
</p>
<p>
<b>Integrated security</b> - Checkmk Cloud has security features such as TLS encryption for network traffic, AES-256 encryption for data at rest,
centralized user access and rights management and is developed by an ISO 27001-certified software vendor.
</p>
<p>
You can find more information about the new Checkmk Cloud on our <a href="https://checkmk.com/product/checkmk-cloud-saas" target="_blank">website</a>.
</p>

</div>
<!-- right column -->
<div class="col">
<div class="ytvideo" id="videocontainer" style="padding-bottom: 0px">
<!-- DO NOT USE YouTube's embed code! Copy the link and the title and create a regular link that is embeddable from it: https://www.youtube.com/embed/video_id -->
<!-- Some JavaScript magic will convert the link to an iframe when the overlay is requested. -->
<!-- No request for the overlay, no cookie from Google. It is that easy. -->
<!-- <a href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/or_w83JzEDI" title="Checkmk live:  New changes and improvements in the agent and the agent bakery with Checkmk 2.1">Watch on YouTube</a> -->
<!--<a href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PzIPNJgARQI" title="Updating Checkmk and using multiple instances">Auf YouTube anschauen</a> -->
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/l0qeiYkmfMo" title="Checkmk live-stream - Get insights into the new Checkmk Cloud">Watch on YouTube</a>
</div><!-- ytvideo -->

<br>
<p>
Checkmk Product Managers Jonas Dieterle and Christian Reiser present the Checkmk Cloud in July 2024 - in the Checkmk live-stream with Community Manager Sara Garifullina.
</p>
<!--
<p>
This User Guide, like the software, is in a state of continuous development.
You will find articles on the current functions of Checkmk Cloud in the User Guide.
</p>
</div>
</div> -->
<!-- Close link -->
<div class="closeonly" style="text-align: right; width: 99%;"><a href="#" class="hidefeatured" onClick="hideFeaturedTopic()">Close</a></div>
</div><!-- topicshadow -->
</div><!-- topicopaque -->
</body>
</html>