<!-- encoding: utf-8 -->
<!-- Must be parsable as XML, otherwise including will fail, check with docserve -->
<html>
<head></head>
<body>
<div id="header"><h1>The official Checkmk Cloud User Guide</h1></div>
<div id="content">
<div class="lbox">
<img src="../images/landingpage_black_mac.png" width="300" />
<div class="paragraph"><p><b>Dear reader</b><br />
We are pleased that you have found to Checkmk Cloud.
Checkmk Cloud provides you with Checkmk as <i>Software as a Service (SaaS)</i> in the cloud.
You can find out what characterizes Checkmk Cloud (SaaS), also in comparison to its self-hosted siblings such as Checkmk Cloud (Self-hosted), in an <a href="./cce.html">own article</a>.
</p></div>
<div class="paragraph"><p>
As a monitoring software, Checkmk offers comprehensive and specialized solutions for dealing with the very diverse environments of IT infrastructures.
This inevitably requires a very comprehensive documentation which goes beyond the mere description of the obvious.
Our User Guide will help you as much as possible to better understand Checkmk, to implement solutions for your requirements with Checkmk, as well as helping you to discover new approaches of solving problems.
</p></div>
<div class="paragraph"><p>
To make the handling of Checkmk as easy as possible, the articles in this User Guide follow rather unusual approaches in many places.
It is almost never a matter of simply copying a prefabricated sequence of individual steps.
Rather, it is intended to give you, the reader, a deeper understanding of a feature in Checkmk.
</p></div>
<div class="paragraph"><p>
To briefly summarize, our most important premise is that the User Guide should be helpful.
And it is most helpful when you can translate our description as a blueprint into a solution for your own problem.
<a href="./welcome.html#landing_page_continue">Read more…</a>
</p></div>
</div>
<div class="outercols">
<div class="col">
<h3>New to Checkmk?</h3>
<p>
There's a first time for everything, even with Checkmk.
Since you will be exposed to a large number of options and functions, sometimes it can be difficult to set the right steps on this journey.
</p>
<p>
Nevertheless, to make sure you can start your first Checkmk monitoring quickly and easily, we have written a 
<a href="./intro_setup.html">Beginner's Guide</a>.
This will give you a compact step-by-step introduction to Checkmk, and it is structured in such a way that you can read it quickly from beginning to end and participate right away.
Therefore, it is short and concise and does not dwell on unnecessary details. 
By the end of the Beginner's Guide you will have a functional Checkmk system.
</p>
</div>
<!-- Leave this empty, it will be replaced by content from featured_NNN.png -->
<div class="col" id="featuredtopic">
</div><!-- class="col" -->
<!-- end placeholder -->
<!-- Leave this empty, it will be filled with auto generated lists -->
<div class="col" id="autolists">
</div><!-- class="col" -->
</div><!-- class="outercols" -->
</body>
</html>
