<!-- encoding: utf-8 -->
<!-- Must be parsable as XML, otherwise including will fail, check with docserve -->
<html>
<head></head>
<body>
<!-- column to show on landingpage -->
<div class="col" id="featuredtopic">
<h3>Featured Topic: Checkmk 2.4.0</h3>
<p>
Checkmk 2.4.0 contains exciting new features, but also many detailed improvements.
The most obvious usability improvement is the complete overhaul of the notification system.
Piggyback can now be used across site boundaries thanks to an additional message broker component.
An OpenTelemetry Collector has been integrated into Checkmk Cloud for the first time as a technical preview.
</p>
<p class="buttonright">
<a href="#" id="morebutton">Find out more ...</a>
</p>
<div id="ytbox">
<img src="../images/featured_23beta.png" />
<!-- <img class="ytpreview" src="../images/featured_000.jpg" /> -->
<div class="ytbanderole">
On YouTube:<br />
<b>Updating Checkmk and using multiple instances</b>
</div>

</div><!-- end id featuredtopic -->
<div>
<!-- the overlay -->
<div id="topicopaque">
<div id="topicshadow">
<div class="innercols">
<!-- left column -->
<div class="col">
<h2>Checkmk 2.4.0 - the highlights</h2>
<img src="../images/CEE.svg" align="left" width="80" style="margin: 10px;" />
<p>
Checkmk 2.4.0 contains exciting new features, but also many detailed improvements.
Read here how you can benefit from the new features.
</p>
<h3>New structures for notifications</h3>
<p>
We have fundamentally redesigned and improved the notifications section. From version 2.4.0, a new overview page provides you with an overview of the most important core data and direct access to all relevant rule sets. At the same time, we have also completely revised the setup of the notification rules. A "Guided mode" now guides you step-by-step through the creation and checking of your notification rules, making your work easier.
</p>
<h3>Dynamic host management</h3>
<p>
With the new release of Checkmk, the dynamic host management has been fundamentally reorganized. The new architecture separates the collection of information from its further processing. This ensures that all data is collected quickly and completely, even in large and highly dynamic environments, and then processed stably and securely.
</p>
<h3>Distributing piggyback data</h3>
<p>
In addition to the complete revision of the dynamic host management, from Checkmk 2.4.0 you can now freely choose on which instance piggyback data should be processed. This allows you to collect data on remote instance A and then forward it to any other remote instance – for example via a peer-to-peer connection – and have the dynamic host management generate the corresponding hosts there.
</p>
<h3>OpenTelemetry</h3>
<p>
In Checkmk 2.4.0 you can receive OpenTelemetry metrics in Checkmk Cloud and Checkmk MSP and process them in the monitoring. Checkmk comes with an OpenTelemetry collector for this purpose. This supports the gRPC and HTTP(S) transport protocols as a receiver. It can also collect data from Prometheus endpoints as a scraper.
Based on the OpenTelemetry services recognized, hosts can be created automatically with the dynamic host management. These hosts are then assigned OpenTelemetry metrics as Checkmk services by a special agent.
The OpenTelemetry integration still has the status of a technical preview, i.e. it will undergo major changes over time.
<p>
<!-- h3>Blog-Artikel</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href=".">Den Push-Agenten unter Linux einrichten</a></li>
<li><a href=".">Den Push-Agenten unter Windows einrichten</a></li>
<li><a href=".">Automatisierungsmöglichkeiten für die Verteilung</a></li>
</ul> -->
</div>
<!-- right column -->
<div class="col">
<!-- <img src="../images/mkp_manager_all_states.png" style="padding: 50px 50px 0px 50px; align:center; width:80%;"/> -->
<!-- <h2>Checkmk Livestream: Der neue Agent</h2> -->

<div class="ytvideo" id="videocontainer" style="padding-bottom: 0px">
<!-- DO NOT USE YouTube's embed code! Copy the link and the title and create a regular link that is embeddable from it: https://www.youtube.com/embed/video_id -->
<!-- Some JavaScript magic will convert the link to an iframe when the overlay is requested. -->
<!-- No request for the overlay, no cookie from Google. It is that easy. -->
<!-- <a href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/or_w83JzEDI" title="Checkmk live:  New changes and improvements in the agent and the agent bakery with Checkmk 2.1">Watch on YouTube</a> -->
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PzIPNJgARQI" title="Updating Checkmk and using multiple instances">Watch on YouTube</a>

</div><!-- ytvideo -->

<h3>User guide articles</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="update.html">Updates and upgrades</a></li>
<li><a href="update_major.html">Update to version 2.4.0</a></li>
<li><a href="backup.html">Backups</a></li>
<li><a href="omd_basics.html">Site administration with omd</a></li>
</ul>
<h3>More information on the topic</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://checkmk.com/download" target="_blank">Download Checkmk</a></li>
<li><a href="https://forum.checkmk.com/" target="_blank">The Checkmk forum</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/checkmk-channel/videos" target="_blank">Subscribe to the Checkmk YouTube channel!</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<!-- Close link -->
<div class="closeonly" style="text-align: right; width: 99%;"><a href="#" class="hidefeatured" onClick="hideFeaturedTopic()">Close</a></div>
</div><!-- topicshadow -->
</div><!-- topicopaque -->
</body>
</html>